Bethune Theatredanse records, 1957-2012
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4: Clippings., 1979-2007.
  - Los Angeles Times - "Time Honors Volunteers for Helping"., 1998. (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Los Angeles Times Orange County - "Shakin' it to the Limit"., 1998. (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - The Orange County Register - "Imagine That"., 1998. (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Santa Ana News - "Russell and Zina at 22nd Very Special Arts Festival"., 1998. (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Los Angeles Times - "Reaching New Heights"., 1999. (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Dance Teacher - "Enabling Through Dance"., 1999. (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Korean language article, possibly Nutcracker., ca. 2000. (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Good Housekeeping - "Profiles: Command Performance"., 2000. (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Santa Barbara News-Press - "Spirit of Creative Dance Works Magic"., 2001. (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Burbank Business Journal - "Now Appearing Our Newest Members!"., 2004. (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Mountain News Newspaper - "Acclaimed Troupe to Perform at Peace Through Music"., 2005. (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - USA Today - "The Inaugural USA Today Hollywood Hero Award Honoring Zina Bethune"., 2006. (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Giving You a Voice - Infinite Dreams., 2006. (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Tolucan Times - "Bethune II Troupe"., 2007. (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Tolucan Times - "Burbank Noon Kiwanis Club Presents Check to BCR A Place To Grow"., 2007. (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - ValleyNews.com - "Kiwanis Donates to Dance Classes for Disabled"., 2007. (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - "Dancing With Heart"., undated. (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - "Zina Bethune Was Born to Dance - There's No Stopping Her"., undated. (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Clipping book., 2010. (Box 57)
- Series 5: Photographs., 1980-2010.
  Photographs of Zina Bethune, including headshots, dance poses, and photos with celebrity friends; Bethune Theatredanse company dancers and productions; and Dance Outreach (later known as Infinite Dreams) students, classes, and events.
  - Subseries 1: Zina Bethune, and Company dancers., 1970s-2008.
    Photographs of Zina Bethune, including headshots and dance poses; Bethune Theatredanse company dancers and productions; and Dance Outreach (later known as Infinite Dreams) students, classes, and events. Many images are available in print, slide, and negative formats.
    - Zina Bethune - headshots., ca. 1970s. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Zina Bethune - headshots., ca. 1980s. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Zina Bethune - headshots., ca. 1991. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Zina Bethune - headshots., 1992. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Zina Bethune - headshot for resume., ca. 1990s. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Zina Bethune - headshot., ca. 1992. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Zina Bethune - headshots., 2000. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Zina Bethune - headshots., ca. 2000s. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Zina Bethune - headshots (CD-R)., 2005. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Zina Bethune - headshots (CD-R; Zip drive)., 2003-2008. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Zina Bethune - Italy headshots; historic photos (CD-Rs)., undated. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Zina Bethune - "The Nurses" images (photocopies)., ca. 1962. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Zina Bethune - TV appearance., 1983. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Zina Bethune - dance pose., 1987. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Zina Bethune - dance pose., ca. 1980s. (Box 10, Folder 15, Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Zina Bethune - dance pose., ca. 1980s. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Zina Bethune - dance pose with partner., ca. 1980s. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Zina Bethune - dance pose with partner., ca. 1980s. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Zina Bethune - performance., ca. 1980s. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Zina Bethune - dance performance with partners., ca. 1980s. (Box 55, Folder 5, Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Zina Bethune - Warner Center performance., 1987-1988. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Zina Bethune - with Mikhail Baryshnikov., ca. 1970s. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Zina Bethune - in Grand Hotel, the Musical (photocopies)., 1989. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Zina Bethune - promotional photo., 1987. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Zina Bethune - with Sylvia Goulden., ca. 1990s. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Zina Bethune - with Elliott Gould, Lee Meriwether., 1980s. (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Zina Bethune - at Shirley MacLaine tribute., 1987. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Zina Bethune - with John Travolta, Shirley MacLaine., 1985. (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Zina Bethune - with Martin Landau and Marci Hannigan., 2000s. (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Zina Bethune - with Lee Meriwether and Marcy Hannigan., 2003. (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Zina Bethune - with celebrities., 1980s-1990s. (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Company dancers., 1980s. (Box 10, Folder 30, Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Company dancers., ca. 1980s. (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Company dancers., 1987. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Company dancers., ca. 1987. (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Company dancers - headshots (CD-R)., 2008. (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Bethune Theatredanse - pictures for slideshow., undated. (Box 10, Folder 35, Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous/unidentified. (Box 61)
  - Subseries 2: Productions., 1981-2007.
    - American in Paris (negatives)., ca. 1990s. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - American in Paris., ca. 2000s. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - American in Paris (contact sheets)., ca. 2000s. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Bird of Passage., ca. 1990. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Bird of Passage (slides)., ca. 1990. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Bird of Passage (negatives, contact sheets)., ca. 1990. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Bird of Passage - opening night., 1990. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - The Collector., ca. 1980s. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Cradle of Fire (slides and negatives)., 1993. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Cradle of Fire., 1993. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Cradle of Fire., 1993. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Fever a la Mode., ca. 1980s. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Frost and Fire., 2002. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Frost and Fire., 2002. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Frost and Fire (negatives and contact sheets)., 2002. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Frost and Fire (negatives and contact sheets)., 2002. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Frost and Fire (CD-R)., 2007. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Galileo, Jupiter, Apollo., ca. 1980s. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Galileo, Jupiter, Apollo (prints, negatives, contact sheets)., ca. 1980s. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Galileo, Jupiter, Apollo (slides used in video)., 1987. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Galileo, Jupiter, Apollo., ca. 1990s. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Galileo, Jupiter, Apollo., ca. 2000. (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Galileo, Jupiter, Apollo., ca. 2000. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Galileo, Jupiter, Apollo., ca. 2000. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Galileo, Jupiter, Apollo., 2000. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Liebslieder Waltzer., circa 1980s. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Liebslieder Waltzer., circa 1980s. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Liebslieder Waltzer., circa 1980s. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Manvantara Game/American in Paris., 2003. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Mind's Eye., 1987-1988. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Mind's Eye., 1987-1988. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Mind's Eye., 1987-1988. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Mind's Eye., 1988. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Roadside Attractions (slides, negatives)., ca. 1987. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Romeo and Juliet., 1981. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Silent Roar (negatives and contact sheets)., 1997. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Silent Roar (negatives)., 1997. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Silent Roar., 1997. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Silent Roar (photocopies)., 1997. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Silent Roar., 2009. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Silent Roar (contact sheets)., 1997. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Silent Roar (CD)., 1997. (Box 61)
    - Swing Shift., ca. 1980s. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - The Trial of St. Joan., 1980s. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Artwork - murals, graffiti (slides, negatives)., ca. 1987. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Artwork - set design (slides)., ca. 1980s. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Artwork - set design (slides)., ca. 1980s. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Artwork - set design., 1980s-1990s. (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Dance Outreach (Infinite Dreams)., 1983-2009.
    - Students - portraits., 2003. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Students - portrait (negatives, contact sheets)., 2003. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Students - portraits (incl. CD-R)., 2004. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Students - portraits (incl. CD-R)., 2004. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Students - Lankershim Arts Center., 1999-2000. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Students - group (negatives, contact sheets)., 2003. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Students - Sarah Anderson with Zina Bethune., 1990. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Students - Sarah Anderson with Zina Bethune (slides)., ca. 1980s. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Students - Russell Bartel., 1999-2000. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Students - Russell Bartel with Zina Bethune., 1999. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Students - Lindsay Berkovitz with Zina Bethune., 1993. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Students - Julissa La Farge with Zina Bethune., ca. 1990s. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Students - Teal Sherer with Zina Bethune., 2008. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Students - Hour Magazine appearance, Sarah Anderson and Zina Bethune., ca. 1990. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Students - artwork (slides)., 1984. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Students - performances (CD-Rs)., 2002-2003. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Students - performances - Help Group., 1980s. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Students - performances., ca. 1990s. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Students - performance preparation with Sylvia Goulden., 1980s. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Class visit - with Zina Bethune., 1980s. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Class visit., ca. 1980s. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Class visit., 1986. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Class visit (negatives, contact sheets)., 1991. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Class visit., ca. 1990s. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Class visit - Columbus School, with Zina Bethune., ca. 1980s. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Class visit - Columbus School., 1984. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Class visit - Columbus School, with Zina Bethune., 1984-1985. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Class visit - Columbus School., 1987. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Class visit - Verdugo Woodlands (slides)., 1986. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Lecture/demo., 1984-1985. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Lecture/demo - Children's Museum., 1987. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Lecture/demo - Verdugo Woodlands., 1985-1986. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Master class., ca. 1986. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Master class., 1992. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Very Special Arts Festival (slides)., 1983. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Very Special Arts Festival., 1985. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Very Special Arts Festival., 1985. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Very Special Arts Festival., 1986. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Very Special Arts Festival., 1987. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Very Special Arts Festival., 1991. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Very Special Arts Festival (slides)., 1992. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Very Special Arts Festival., 1993. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Very Special Arts Festival., 2001. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Very Special Arts Festival (CD-R)., 2007, 2008. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Very Special Arts Festival., 2009. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Imagination Celebration., 2006. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - International Circus Day., 1993. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Carpi, Italy trip (CD-R)., 2003. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Japan trip., 2000. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Japan trip (slides)., 2000. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Japan trip (undeveloped film)., 2000. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Fundraiser - Gallerie Michael., 1986. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Fundraiser - Odyssey Theatre., ca. 1980s. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Fundraiser - Orange County Main Place., 1997-1998. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Friendraiser - Lankershim Arts Center., 2000. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Dreams Come True., 1980s. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Dreams Come True., 1980s. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Dreams Come True., 1985. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Dreams Come True., 1986?. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Dreams Come True., 1987. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Dreams Come True., 1987. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Dreams Come True., 1980s. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Dreams Come True., 1980s. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Dreams Come True., 1989. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Dreams Come True (negatives, slides, contact sheets)., 1989. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Hollywood Hero Awards - still photos (CD-R)., 2009. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Hollywood Hero Awards - slideshow (CD-R)., 2006. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Santa Barbara Auxiliary celebration., 2001. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Can Can Entertainment Group., 2002. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Celebrity headshots., 1980s. (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Series 6: Audio-Visual., 1957-2010.
  Primarily video footage of Bethune Theatredanse and Dance Outreach (later Infinite Dreams) productions and activities. Includes promos, performances, rehearsals, interviews, clips from television appearances, and tours. Also includes acting demos and footage for Zina Bethune and her mother, Ivy Bethune. Formats include VHS, U-Matic, Beta-SP, Mini DV, Hi-8, DVD, CD, and DAT. For a more detailed list, please consult collection folder.
  COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
  - Infinite Dreams (formerly known as Dance Outreach)., 1980-2010.
    - Promos., 1987-2008. (Box 18-19)
      Promos for Dance Outreach and Infinite Dreams, featuring a variety of performances including "From the Heart," "The Mike and Maty Show," "The Dance Within" and several Telethon appearances. Includes masters, raw footage, and edits.
    - From the Heart; Heart Dancing., 1987. (Box 19)
      Zina Bethune and Sarah Anderson performing "From the Heart" and "Heart Dancing." Includes footage from KCET California Stories and the NBC's Kennedy Center special.
    - Classes., 1980s-2009. (Box 20-22)
      Documentation of Dance Outreach/Infinite Dreams classes and workshops at Los Angeles area schools and other locations.
    - Performances., 1993-2010. (Box 23-26)
      Footage of Dance Outreach/Infinite Dreams performances, often featuring Zina Bethune with students, including Sarah Anderson, Russell Bartel, and Lindsay Berkovitz. Includes performances from the North Hollywood Festival, LA Open Arts, A Very Special Arts Festival, the Feather Awards, television shows, and others.
    - Tours., 2000-2003. (Box 26-28)
      Performance and rehearsal footage from Infinite Dreams tours, including Italy, Japan, China, and Geneva, Switzerland.
    - Broadcast., 1984-2000. (Box 29-30)
      Dance Outreach/Infinite Dreams footage from broadcast television, including excerpts from local newscasts and programs such as Great Day America and Good Day LA.
    - Doctors for Dance Outreach., 1996. (Box 31)
      Edited and raw footage used to make promos featuring doctors interviews.
    - Friendraiser., 1998-2000. (Box 32)
      Footage from the Infinite Dreams/Dance Outreach benefits known as Friendraisers.
    - Very Special Arts Festival (VSAF)., 1995-2009. (Box 33)
      Footage from Infinite Dreams/Dance Outreach participation in the Very Special Arts Festivals.
    - Teacher/Dancer auditions., 1995-2009. (Box 34)
      Footage of Infinite Dreams/Dance Outreach teachers, including some audition tapes.
  - Bethune Theatredanse., 1980-2008.
    - Promos., 1980-2008. (Box 35-36)
      A variety of promos for Bethune Ballet and Bethune Theatredanse, many from the early 1980s and featuring Zina Bethune's celebrity friends. Includes masters as well as edited and extended versions.
    - Excerpts., 1988-2005. (Box 37-38)
      Short excerpts from various Bethune Theatredanse productions, including Galileo/Jupiter/Apollo, Mind's Eye, Silent Roar, Cradle of Fire, and American in Paris. Some tapes include Infinite Dreams/Dance Outreach footage as well.
    - Bethune Ballet - early performances., 1981-1982. (Box 59-60)
      Master videotape and 16mm film of early Bethune Ballet performances. One marked Internal Footage from first Bethune Ballet performance at Embassy Theatre. 16mm film is "The American" and "The Collector."
    - An American in Paris., 1998-2000. (Box 38)
      Rehearsal and performance footage. Includes masters, multiple camera angles, and music.
    - Ballets., 1980-1990. (Box 39)
      Footage of early Bethune Ballet/Bethune Theatredanse performances, including Romeo & Juliet, The Trial of St. Joan, Don Quixote, Leibesleider Walzer, Somewhere in Time, and Bird of Passage.
    - Cradle of Fire., 1993-2000. (Box 40)
      Footage of Bethune Theatredanse original production that tells the story of two teenagers, one living in Nazi Germany and the other on the streets of 1990s Los Angeles. Includes promos, excerpts, and masters.
    - Frost and Fire., 2000-2007. (Box 41-43, Box 61)
      Footage of Bethune Theatredanse adaptation of Ray Bradbury's short story about a planet where a human's lifespan is only eight days. Includes promos, scene excerpts, rehearsals, and full performances from multiple camera angles. CD/DVD copies are in Box 60.
    - Galileo, Jupiter, Apollo., 1987-1999. (Box 44-45)
      Footage of Bethune Theatredanse's multimedia exploration into science fiction and technology, inspired by John Wehrle's Los Angeles mural of the same name. Includes audio files, music, excerpts, and performances for LA Open Arts, Dance Roots, and others.
    - The Manvantara Game., 1996-1998. (Box 46)
      Footage of Bethune Theatredanse's multimedia exploration of Shamanism in the past, present, and future. Primarily multiple camera footage of original performances at Los Angeles Contemporary Exhibitions.
    - Mind's Eye., 1988. (Box 47)
      Footage of Bethune Theatredanse's production based on the C.S. Lewis science fiction story Perelandra. Includes promos, raw footage, and performances.
    - Silent Roar., 1997. (Box 48)
      Footage of Bethune Theatredanse multimedia production based on the journey of a gray whale. Includes promos, multiple camera angles, and masters.
    - Music., 1970s-1980s. (Box 61)
      Reel-to-reels, 45rpm discs, and a cassette, mostly unidentified but may contain music for older productions.
  - Other., 1957-2006. (Box 49-51)
    - Zina Bethune., 1957-2006. (Box 49-51, Box 59)
      Footage of Zina Bethune. Includes acting demo as well as copies of her performances in Who's That Knocking at My Door, and a variety of TV shows throughout the 1960s-1980s. Also includes the 1957 broadcast of The Nutcracker, in which she played the part of Clara; documentation of her efforts to walk after surgery; and appearances in interviews and award shows.
    - Dancer/Choreographer demos., 1990s-2000. (Box 52)
      Names include Gene Bua, Twyla Tharp, Morawski, Randy Allaire, Ann Marie Melendez, Karina del Mar, Janice Cronkhite, Jina, Stephanie Lightburn, Marnie Baker, Leyda Sol Garcia, Lisa Street, Charles David Anderson, Lisa Goldin, Natalie Bowers, Amelia Kinkade, Michael Massucci, and 3 Hip Hop dancers.
    - Disability organizations/other dance groups., 1993-2002. (Box 53)
      Promotional material from Wheels for Humanity, Lymphatic Research Foundation, Youth Leadership Forum, Rife Technology, and Tod Hillman-Strong Productions. Performances by Tobinworld, LA Chamber Ballet, and Heidelberger Ballet.
    - Stockholders meeting., 1999. (Box 53)
      5 tapes featuring interviews with Zina Bethune and Dr. Charles Engh.
    - Ivy Bethune., 1989-1993. (Box 54)
      Demo reels and copies of Ivy Bethune's various TV appearances.
    - Unidentified VHS., undated. (Box 54)
    - Unidentified CD/DVD. (Box 61)